# ANIL KUMAR

2819 North Shiloh Road, Garland, TX 75044 +14699207165

Email: er.anilkaushik@gmail.com, LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/anil02

Competent & target oriented with experience of 13 Years 9 Months Total, 7 years of Python Development & 6.9 years of Telecom Experience. While performing in the cost-efficient manner along with the unwavering quality standards. Currently spearheading as Automation Architect with Ericsson Global India Pvt Ltd. where I have designed a rule-based platform in Python that deployed on ubuntu server as a containerized application.

### **EXPERIENCE**

APR 2023 - PRESENT

## **SR RF ENGINEER, VEDANTA TELECOM LLC**

Discover and implement automation scope in different telecom verticals.

**SEPT 2020 - MAR 2023** 

## **AUTOMATION ARCHITECT, ERICSSON GLOBAL INDIA PVT LT**

Design and Develop Python auto Bots for delivery teams working on telecom activities like Commissioning, Integration, Optimization, KPI Monitoring & Design.

- Delivery Connector (Python Microservices, MongoDB Aggregation):

  Takes Json Rule Input from GUI. Convert Rule into MongoDB Aggregation

  Query. Apply the bulk query on user's event collection, find matches and create next delivery workorder.
- Site Tracker Actualization (Python Threading Microservices, Docker Container, Kafka): Read Mapper Excel File using API's, uploaded by Delivery Managers and Implementation Managers on Microsoft SharePoint location, managed by. Read Data from Salesforce tool using API. After processing multiple sources information actualize the activities milestone accordingly.
- ➤ NPI Capacity Analyzer (Python, Ubuntu, PM2 Service, SQL): Developed and integrated TMO NPI auto bot which will download huge network level data from Performance tool, then produce multiple reports charts on hourly and daily basis to identify capacity crunch. Final report will be uploaded on SharePoint to be accessed by teams.
- > SharePoint Scanner (Python, MongoDB, Docker Container, RabbitMQ):
  Developed auto bot SharePoint Scanner which will search for different project
  folders and capture updated file date stamps, file names and content. Then
  after performing ETL jobs feed power BI tool for further analysis.

- ➤ GPL audit Auto Bot (Python, MongoDB, PM2 Services): Developed GPL audit bot which will fetch data based on GPL file from Parameter Configuration Tool and Network Design tool, then find the missing configuration values or discrepancy reports.
- ➤ RFST reporting Bot (Python, RabbitMQ, Docker Container, SQL): Developed rule-based bot which will fetch RFST stress test report from tool using API and orchestrate all steps during whole activity which consists manual triggers also. SQL queries applied with Python to extract table output from database in format.

#### **NOV 2019 - SEPT 2020**

## **ENGINEER V, ERICSSON INC**

Team Lead for 4G,5G Commissioning and Integration Team. Automate Scripts creation using RFDS & CIQ information. Automate daily delivery tracking & weekly Monthly reporting dashboards using Python and Alteryx.

- Had worked closely with Appian application developer to create logic which takes input from excel sheet and output commissioning script.
- CIQ audit, Create XML Commissioning script. Integration of New Nokia AirScale Macro eNodeB (BBU) remotely. Troubleshooting RET, VSWR & other hardware/software alarms

#### MAR 2015 - NOV 2019

#### **SPECIALIST.** ERICSSON INDIA GLOBAL PVT LTD

- ➤ Auto Integration Tool (Python Shell Scripting): Developed integration scripts to integrate multiple nodes and carriers in one go by taking configuration commands from configuration files.
- ➤ Audit tool (Python): Developed a Data audit tool using Python Language (X2 link -Parameter auditor) The tool picks up BTS usage data from ~90 markets and performs a series of complex calculations and algorithms resulting in erroneous data flagging throughout the millions of lines in merely 5 minutes which was a mammoth task of around 8 hours prior to this automation.
- > VB-Scripting & Python Shell Scripting Automated a highly manual task of matching, validating and correcting various parameters of eNodeB data. The scripts login to the multiple hosts automatically for extracting desired data and perform the audit steps to capture and log the erroneous data. The user gets a summarized report of errors.
- ➤ Data formatting tool (Python) Have developed this tool using Python has a GUI to select multiple data sources at once. Comprised of more than 50 complex transformations that make sense out of unformatted data feeds. Ultimately, tool outputs the user consumable formatted data in excel files.

- Complete Remote site acceptance by checking test results of RSRP, RSRQ, SINR, Throughput etc.
- Support Legacy swap to BBU or Cabinet Swap activity remotely, with per-post analysis till acceptance.

#### NOV 2010 - MAR 2015

## **SENIOR ENGINEER, ERICSSON INDIA GLOBAL PVT LTD**

- Worked on creating CFR (Carrier Funding Request) and Plumbing diagram of sites, including site survey for hardware installation space availability, including BBU, RRH, CSR Router, Fiber length etc.
- Responsible for the execution of all equipment Modifications/Installations which include creation of detailed statement of work packages (MOP).
- Conduct survey audit for new IBS site, including Fiber requirement and hardware space availability.

#### JUNE 2009 - NOV 2010

#### BTS ENGINEER, ADECCO FLEXIONE WORKFORCE SOLUTION PVT LTD

- > Create Config file and commission 2G BTS. Rectifying the alarms of sites
- Responsible for preparing RF & RFI survey reports. Quality Audits & power calibration of BTS. Preparing design sheet & survey drawings. given by OMC-R team & implement software migration.
- Provide training to vendor team for installation and commissioning of site. Maintaining records regarding site optimization, antenna details, BTS type, E1 ports.

## **EDUCATION**

**JAN 2009** 

**POST GRADUATE DIPLOMA IN WIRELESS TECHNOLOGY AND APPLICATION, CDEC**NOIDA INDIA

**JUNE 2007** 

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY, KURUKSHETRA UNIVERSITY KURUKSHETRA INDIA

## **SKILLS**

- Python 3
- Python Microservices
- Flask (REST API's)
- Ubuntu
- PM2 Services, Cron Job (Ubuntu)
- Spark
- Docker Container
- Alteryx

- MongoDB
- RabbitMQ
- Kafka
- Nginx, uWSGI
- SharePoint API's
- ELK Logging
- Azure DevOps
- Git Version Controlling

## **ACTIVITIES**

- Automation Fundamental Level Assessment Certified
- Automation Experienced Level Assessment Certified